Okay, we are going to continue and learn
how
these different energy jumps can have
different
effects. Let's say we have an atom over
here.
I'm not going to draw the bottom half,
this
would just be the nucleus. Over time, the
charge
or the pull from the protons will decrease
because
the distance is getting further, and also
of other regions such as shielding and
effective
nuclear charge, but that's mostly
chemistry.
So, we're just going to treat it as higher
distance
results in less attraction.
So, that means that as you go out, n
equals
1, 2, 3, the distance between these gets
smaller
and smaller until you get to infinity.
And there isn't really an infinity shell,
it
just means that the electron has left the
atom,
or ionization energy, and we're not going
to
go too much into that, because that's
chemistry.
So, that means that when an electron jumps
from
energy level 1 to 2 versus when an
electron
jumps from energy level 2 to 3, the energy
required
for it to jump from 1 to 2 is greater
because
the distance is greater. And same thing
when
you're going the opposite way, when energy
or
a photon is emitted here, it's going to
emit
a photon with a higher wavelength, or less
energy,
than if an electron jumps from 2 to 1.
And that's basically convergence.
Another formula you need to know is f
equals
c over lambda, the speed of light over the
wavelength.
And these two formulas are the main things
you
need to know for this unit. And when you
combine
them and derive them, you also get e
equals
h times f, which you could use, it's also
useful.
But just know these two and you'll be all
set.
Yeah, that's basically all for blackbody
radiation
and how atoms or materials can absorb and
emit
energy. Furthermore, the wavelength of the
energy
characterizes what type of radiation it
is.
For example, infrared radiation typically
has
a lower wavelength.
And UV radiation typically has a higher
wavelength
and visible is in the middle, with red
being
the lowest and violet being the highest.
And yeah, that's a bit about the
electromagnetic
spectrum and how materials can emit and
absorb
radiation. Thanks for watching!